(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T08:09:13.715573",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
括目せよ
Bear witness!
プロデューサー!!!
Producer!!!
どうしたんですか、ラプラスさん
What is it, La+?
次の生誕ライブ、なんにもやることないんですけど!!
I have nothing planned for my next birthday live!!
毎年いろいろやってきたけど…
We've done various things every year...
去年は、ミームやりすぎて、ミームキャラになっちゃったし、どうしよう？
Last year I went too hard on memes and became a meme character. What should I do?
デビュー当時のアイドルらしさはもう見る影もないですからね
There's hardly any trace of your debut idol persona left, after all.
若輩はどうやっていけばいいんだー
How's a rookie supposed to get by here?!
勝手にTire表とか作っちゃいましたし…
You went ahead and made a Tier list on your own...
それだ！
That's it!
ほら、若輩、お姉さん大好きでしょ？
Look, rookie, you love older sisters, don't you?
？？？？
????
ホロライブのお姉さんを大集合させよう！
Let's gather all the Hololive big sisters!
お姉さんライブだ！！！
An older sister live concert!!!
….
....
大丈夫だよ！
It'll be fine!
当てはある！！若輩に任せとけ！
I've got a plan!! Leave it to me!
それはちゃんとラプラスさんのライブとして成立するんですか？
Will that actually work as Laplace-san's concert?
そこは…なんかいい感じにやるんだよ！
That part... we'll just make it feel right somehow!
ていうか、若輩のこと好きなファンならさ、やっぱり、若輩が好きなことしてるところ、楽しく見てくれるんじゃない！？
I mean, if they're fans who like me, wouldn't they enjoy watching me do what I love?!
限度があるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there a limit to that?
とにかく、やるって決めたらやるの！いくぞー！！！
Anyway, once I decide to do something, I do it! Let's go—!!!
ノエルさん！
Noel-san!
どうしたの？ラプちゃん？
What's wrong, Lap-chan?
実は、もうすぐ若輩の生誕ライブがあるんですけど、よかったらノエルさんにも出てほしいなって…
Actually, my birthday live is coming up soon, and I was wondering if you'd like to perform in it, Noel-san...
えー！ラプちゃん誘ってくれるの！嬉しい！もちろんだよ！
Eh?! Lap-chan is inviting me? I'm so happy! Of course!
よーし、団長、歌とダンス頑張っちゃうかな！先輩として、かっこいいところ見せちゃうよー！！！
Alright, as the leader, I'll do my best at singing and dancing! As a senior, I'll show you how cool I can be—!!!
あ、いや、歌は若輩がやるんで…ね?ほら、これ持って！
Ah, no, I'll be doing the singing... right? Here, hold this!
え、なになに？どういうこと？これってうちわ？
Eh, what, what? What do you mean? Is this a fan?
さて、あとは何を歌うかですね…
Now, as for what else to sing...
一曲目はね、きっとノエルさんも喜んでくれるはず！
For the first song, I'm sure Noel-san will be happy too!
え？団長が？
Eh? The leader?
去年からノエルさんの影響からか若輩のファン層が広がって、こういう曲が喜んでもらえるかなーって思って！
Ever since last year, maybe because of your influence, my fanbase has grown, so I thought they'd love a song like this!
えー！！期待しちゃうけど…いいののお！？
Eh!! I'm getting my hopes up... Is that really okay?!
良いですよー！一曲目盛り上がっていきましょー！
It's good! Let's get the first song hyped up—!
存外見掛け倒しな 虚勢張ってるロマンス
Don't be fooled by my bluffing, pretentious romance
組み替えちゃって遺伝子 only lonely emergency
Rewriting my DNA in this only lonely emergency
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗せた感情論
Sentimentality riding on static-y radio waves
僕のアピール見逃さないでよ
Don't miss my desperate appeal!
人間なんてだれだって
Everyone's just human, right?
こういうのが好きなんだって
Acting like this is what you love, huh?
一人善がりオーガズミネーション
A self-righteous orgasm - nation
溢れてドヴァドヴァ
Overflowing and gushing out
年季入りなあざとさ
Seasoned and calculated cuteness
「好き」の塗りたくり
Slathered in layers of "I love you"s
決めるぜ僕の8点
Nailing my 8 points!
Love Valigarmanda
膨らんじゃったやっぱおピカゲン
It's swollen up now, my high-voltage condition
最高潮のをくれてやる
I'll give you the ultimate climax!
好きって言葉で貶して
Degrading me with the word "love"
迎え撃つから君のアイデンティティティティティティティティーン
I'll counterattack with your identity-ty-ty-ty-ty-teen!
怯わないで夢見がちボーイ
Don't be timid, dreamy boy
意外とありなんだって
Thinking it might actually work out
気付いて妄想フラストレーション
Realize it, this delusional frustration
毛頭暴走止まらない
My wild thoughts won't stop at all
ギガンティック
Gigantic!
よそ見厳禁見て見て見てね?
No looking away, look, look, look at me, okay?
3 2 1 で目覚めて
Wake up on 3, 2, 1
恋に落ちたりなんかして
And fall completely in love
わし掴んでシークレット
Grab hold of it in secret!
あなんだやっぱ単純で
Ah, it turns out it's so simple after all
僕にとって僕が
To me, I am
揺るぎない絶対王政
My own unshakable absolute monarchy!
だからね君だって
That's why even you
僕が大好きでしょ?
Must adore me, right?
見せ付けるぜ聖域
I'll show you my sacred sanctuary,
僕だけの領域
My exclusive domain!
息継ぎドキドキ優しくしてバカ
Panting, heart racing, be gentle with me, baka~
山盛りなあいうおんちゅ
Piled high with a mountain of "I want you"s
アガっちって恥じらっちって
Getting hyped up, getting embarrassed
狂っちまえばイージーモード
Go crazy and it's easy mode!
油断大敵マジモード
Lower your guard and it's serious mode!
とろとろに溶かして愛need you
Melt away completely, I need your love!
誤算過ぎた僕のエラーフラップ
My miscalculated error trap
ここは限界突破ラブゲーム
This is our limit-breaking love game!
加速しちゃって
Accelerating now,
やばおぴ加減最高超のを
Give me your absolute highest voltage!
見せてやれ
Show it off!
駆け引き上手な僕がルール
I make the rules as a master of pushing and pulling,
狙い撃ち君をプラマイプラスで
Shooting straight at you with plus-minus-plus!
引き返せない二人だけの秘密
There's no turning back from our secret for two
意外とありかもなんて
Thinking it might actually work,
気付いた?罪作りラブポーション
Did you notice? My heart-stealing love potion!
一切合切止められない
There's no stopping it whatsoever,
ギガンティック
Gigantic!
目移りなんて許さないね?
You won't look anywhere else, will you?
ね? 落ちちゃえ!
Right? Fall for me!
ギガンティックO.T.Nの解説だ!
Here's the explanation of Gigantic O.T.N!
主に突き出すものなので下ネタ要素リリィー大歓迎である
Mainly thrusting things upward, so adult humor references are totally welcome!
最近は
Lately,
傷付け合って
Hurting each other
世代のO.T.Nで駆けてくぜもっともっと
Running through generations of O.T.N, more and more!
ラスジが楽しいをとらえたまま打ち付けると思ってなくて
Not expecting the final verse to keep capturing all the fun,
止まんないギガンティック！
It won't stop, gigantic!
膨らんじゃったやっぱおピカゲン
It's swollen up now, my high-voltage condition
最高潮のをくれてやる
I'll give you the ultimate climax!
好きって言葉で貶して
Degrading me with the word "love"
迎え撃つから君のアイデンティティティティティティティティーン
I'll counterattack with your identity-ty-ty-ty-ty-teen!
怯わないで夢見がちボーイ
Don't be timid, dreamy boy
意外とありなんだって
Thinking it might actually work out
気付いて妄想フラストレーション
Realize it, this delusional frustration
毛頭暴走止まらない
My wild thoughts won't stop at all
ギガンティック
Gigantic!
よそ見厳禁見て見て見てね?
No looking away, look, look, look at me, okay?
3 2 1 で目覚めて
Wake up on 3, 2, 1
恋に落ちたりなんかして
And fall completely in love
わし掴んでシー...
Grab hold of it in se...
存外見掛け倒しな
Go on and think that this is love
虚勢張ってるロマンス
But I'm just doing what I must
組み替えちゃって遺伝子
To fix "lonely emergencies"
オンリー・ロンリー・エマージェンシー
You can't expect romance from lust
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗せた感情論
Attachment, love and all that stuff
僕のアピール見逃さないでよ
Don't let that steal from my appeal
やどやどやどやどやど
Appeal, appeal, appeal, appeal!
人間なんてだれだってさ
We all seem to think this is fun
こういうのが好きなんだってさ
I guess it's in our nature, huh?
一人善がりオーガズミネーション 溢れてドヴァドヴァ
It's like we're one big "orgasmy-nation"
年季入りなあいさつ
Immoral acts and terms of service
「好き」の塗りたくり
Lying with a fake "love ya"
決めるぜ僕の8点ラヴァーリガルマンダ
Sticky situations, a multi-person love
リガルマンダ
It's all swollen up now...
さすがに先輩をファン扱いするのはどうかと思いますよ？
Don't you think treating your senior like a fan is a bit much?
いや、ノエルさんはファンでしょ！ファンって言うか、ママになろうとしてる人…？
No, Noel-san is a fan! Well, more like trying to be a mom...?
とにかく、めっちゃ盛り上がってましたやん！
Anyway, it got super hyped up!
てかてかお姉さんといえば、ホロライブって学校みたいじゃない？
Speaking of older sisters, Hololive is kinda like a school, right?
学校？
School?
学校のみんなのアイドル…そらさん
The school's idol... Sora-san.
隣のクラスの留学生…キアラさん
The transfer student from next class... Kiara-san.
凛とした清楚な先輩…AZKiさん
The composed, pure senior... AZKi-san.
部活の先輩お姉さま…ネリッサ
The upperclassman club senior... Nerissa.
クールビューティーな先生…クロニー
The cool beauty teacher... Kronii.
そして、同じクラスにいる、うるさい幼馴染の同級生…いろは
And the noisy childhood friend classmate in the same class... Iroha.
そうだ！これをライブでやれば、盛り上がること間違いなし！
That's right! If we do this at the live, it'll definitely be a hit!
そうと決まれば早速突撃だー!!!!
Decided, time to rush inー!!!!
次から次へとすごい行動力だ…
Such incredible drive, one after another...
いろはー!!!!
Irohaー!!!!
うん？なんでござるか？
Hm? What is it?
ライブでやりたい曲あるんだけど、見ててくんない？
There's a song I want to do at the live, can you watch me?
？？見る？？どういうことでござる？
?? Watch?? What do you mean by that?
そう！見るだけ！やっぱり幼馴染と言えばいつでも見守ってくれる存在だからね…ただそこにいるだけで良い、そばにいてくれるだけ、その温かさが沁みるんだ
That's right! Just watch! Childhood friends always watch over you...
え…なんか気持ち悪いでござる…
Eh... That feels kinda creepy...
いいからいいから！さ、行くぞー！！！
Fine, fine! Now, let's goー!!!
存外見掛け倒しな
Go on and think that this is love
虚勢張ってるロマンス
But I'm just doing what I must
組み替えちゃって遺伝子
To fix "lonely emergencies"
オンリー・ロンリー・エマージェンシー
You can't expect romance from lust
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗せた感情論
Attachment, love and all that stuff
僕のアピール見逃さないでよ
Don't let that steal from my appeal
やどやどやどやどやど
Appeal, appeal, appeal, appeal!
人間なんてだれだってさ
We all seem to think this is fun
こういうのが好きなんだってさ
I guess it's in our nature, huh?
一人善がりオーガズミネーション 溢れてドヴァドヴァ
It's like we're one big "orgasmy-nation"
年季入りなあいさつ
Immoral acts and terms of service
「好き」の塗りたくり
Lying with a fake "love ya"
決めるぜ僕の8点ラヴァーリガルマンダ
Sticky situations, a multi-person love
膨らんじまったやばおぴ加減
It's all swollen up now, it's starting to get messy
最高潮なのを与えてやる！
Go faster, make me climax already
好きって言葉で縋って迎撃すから君のアイデンティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティティ
Tease me and I'll tease you with words of "I love you"
ほらちょっとだけねちょっとだけ見せてちょっとだけねあとね、何やってる？え、え、え、え、何々？何々？ねえ、なになに、なに、なに、なに、なに、なに、ね、な、な、な、な、なんで？ちょっとなんか気持ち悪いでござる…いいからいいから！さ、行くぞー！！！
Make you think it's just between you and m-m-me
ピピピピピッとバースト マスディセイシンセイシンのテケテケテクのナミシダイダイザカリナカナカナカナカドキットシちゃうキミノキミノキミノキミノキミノノキミのファッキンコースティックコースティックマットコースティックコースティックちょっとコークスせめてエイビシディヤス！
Could you hate someone who's so dreamy? There's no way
ステッステッソクモマヤッポガマンデキナイシタシタシシュンキデソトコロコロモおっこうしちゃだめか？え？さんかくねんのうぎしんでおとめではつしきなさきせんぱいそんなにこうちかづけられたらもどけだきたまんなくてああまってせいりのすきまきらめしてーっとごせんちょっとかせいはいこっそりきいちゃってるよ！えっといってうーけーちーエイケーエイゴヒゲノオシャヤキせんぱいねがくほぶせんうえにつったしたにうっとさやあるじょうじょしてきたのここのせんしゅっとぼのとめられないほのおれのしししせっくす ばーい！
Make me go mad, drive me far over the edge tonight
ギガンティックO.T.N
Gigantic O.T.N performance continues...
サヨナラ三角形
Goodbye, triangle,
方程式先生
quadratic equation teacher,
皆さん お・ぴん・こ・ぶ・ーす！
everyone, o-pin-co-booth!
元気すぎんだろ
You're way too energetic!
ピンとバズマス リセイシセイシ
Pin and buzz, reason and sanity,
乗ってってくどなみし...
riding along...
なかなかね 仲良くなっちゃう
It's hard to get along...
不安になってきたけど、大丈夫ぞ？
I'm getting a bit worried, but is that okay?
あ、最後までね、お楽しみにね！緊張で...多分声震えてる...
Ah, until the very end, look forward to it! I'm so nervous... my voice is shaking...
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
マジで色ハズ、ビジネスでよかったー！
Seriously, thank goodness this is just business!
ギムギム、バイバーイ！
Duty calls, bye-bye!
じゃね、帰るね！
See ya, I'm heading back!
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
ねぇねぇ、プロデューサーの好みってどんな人なん？
Hey hey, what kind of person is the producer's type?
え…
Eh...
ほら、ホロライブっていろんな人いるじゃん？
Look, there are all sorts of people in Hololive, right?
しゅぴしゅわー、すーの充電足りてるー？
Shupi-shuwa, is Su's battery fully charged?
水宮すくだよー！
It's Mizumiya Su!
わっしょい！ホロライブの清楚担当！みんなのアイドル、
Wasshoi! Hololive's purity representative! Everyone's idol,
夏色まつりでーす！
Natsuiro Matsuri!
みなさん、待ったかネー！
Everyone, kept you waiting!
ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
I am Takane Lui, holoX's female executive!
はーい、みなさま～、こんらみ～！
Hii, everyone~, Konlami~!
ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Hololive 5th gen's face and liver, Yukihana Lamy!
Good evening! My Cute students. ちょっこーん！
Good evening! My Cute students. Chokoon!
ホロライブ2期生、悪魔のバーチャル保健医 癒月ちょこでえす！ちょっこーん！
Hololive 2nd gen, demonic virtual nurse Yuzuki Choco! Chokoon!
Ahoy! ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンでずー！
Ahoy! Hololive 3rd gen, Houshou Marine, captain of the Houshou Pirates!
みなさんとても魅力です？
Everyone is very attractive?
いやいや、そういうんじゃないでしょ
No, no, that's not what I meant.
いやぁ～仕事ですからね ホロライブの方…とかではないですよ
Well, it's for work... not that they're from Hololive or anything.
ぷーん
Hmph.
ただ、最近の趣味といえば…
However, speaking of recent hobbies...
え…いや…それは…さすがに…すごい趣味してるな…
Eh... no... that's... as expected... quite a unique hobby...
この人に言われたくないな…
I don't want to be told that by you...
あ、こんな時間じゃん！わがはいちょっとこの後用事あるんで…じゃ！
Ah, look at the time! I've got some business to attend to after this... see ya!
初めて読んじゃったぜ…
I finally read it...
きゃべ…高かった！
Cabbage... was expensive!
でも、うまかったからいっか！
But it was tasty, so whatever!
ジャケットとか…クリーニングしよ…
Jacket and stuff... I need to get it cleaned...
来ちゃった…
It's here...
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た ノーサンキュー！
When I called for delivery, you came. No thank you!
それじゃちょっと息抜きでもしましょうか
Then shall we take a little breather?
って感じでチラシの番号見て
With that feeling, looking at the number on the flyer...
たままたどんぴしゃで気に入った子がいたんで
By chance, I found a girl who hit the spot and caught my eye,
胸の大きいのをチョイス
and chose one with big breasts.
髪型少々ドレスエメンのが得意だと
Since her hairstyle and dress sense are her strong suits,
今からそちらへお送りいたしますって
"We will dispatch her to your location now,"
ドアを開けたら別れた彼女
when I opened the door, it was my ex-girlfriend!
おいおいこいつは一体何なのだんだ
Hey hey, what on earth is this all about?!
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た うつろな目をしちゃってだんだ
When I called for delivery, you came, giving me a hollow stare.
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰ってきましたって
"I've come back transformed into your ideal type," you said.
ロミジュリ並の悲劇に酔い 傷つきはしたとポリストが
Intoxicated by a tragedy worthy of Romeo and Juliet, the police...
ガイドラインを見定だして
assessing the guidelines...
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た ノーサンキュー！
When I called for delivery, you came. No thank you!
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぴかない
Love's spoiler, "Separation" sounds like that.
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぴかない
Life's spoiler, "Death" sounds like that.
なにそれ意味深で かっこいいじゃん...
What is that? It's profound and sounds cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ 失礼
You're dancing with a collection of words that sound like that. Excuse me.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
ぴかない ぴかない
It sounds like that, it sounds like that.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
神っぽいな
It's God-ish.
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ
It's okay, it's okay, that.
もういいぜ もういいぜ 逆に興奮してきたな
It's okay, it's okay, I'm actually getting excited.
おっきいね おっきいね 夢
It's big, it's big, dream.
おっきいね おっきいね
It's big, it's big.
景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
Business is good, but morality is THE END.
うぇえい うぇえい
Ueei, ueei...
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's God-ish, that's cowardly.
神っぽいな それ "my god"
It's God-ish, that's "my god".
アイウオンチュウ ウォンチュウ IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, I want you, the feeling that my IQ is dropping.
邪心っぽいな それ 畢竟
It's evil-ish, that's, after all.
邪心っぽいな それ "my god"
It's evil-ish, that's "my god".
アイヘイチュー ヘイチュー 害虫はどっち
I hate you, I hate you, which one is the vermin?
その髪型 その目 その口元
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth,
その香水 その服 そのメイク
That perfume, those clothes, that makeup.
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯
It's that-ish, that's cowardly.
アレっぽいな それ
It's that-ish, that...
その名言 その意見 その批評
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism,
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense.
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's God-ish, that's cowardly.
ぽいな ぽいな ぽいな 憧れちゃう！
Sounds like that, sounds like that, sounds like that, I yearn for it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
ぴかない ぴかない
It sounds like that, it sounds like that.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
神っぽいな
It's God-ish.
メタ思考する本質は恶意？
The essence of meta-thinking is malice?
人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
Intentions that seem to make fun of people.
無為に生き延びるのは難しい
It's hard to survive aimlessly.
権力に呑まれて揺らぐ灯り
Lights that waver, swallowed by power.
神を否定し神に成り代わり
Denying God and taking God's place,
玉座で豹変する小物達
Small-minded people who change on the throne.
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り
A prayer of self-admonition disguised as criticism.
"Do you know?"
何言ってんの？ それ意味がよくわかんないし
What are you saying? That's annoying, what are you saying? That's...
眠っじまうよ マジ
I don't really understand the meaning, and I'll fall asleep, seriously.
飽きっぴなんだ オーケー
You get bored easily, okay.
みんな飽きっぴなんだ オーケー
Everyone gets bored easily, okay.
踊れるやつちょうだいちょだいビーム...
Give me a danceable guy, give me a beam...
キスっぽいね キスっぽいね それ
It's kiss-ish, it's kiss-ish, that.
キスっぽいね キスっぽいね 逆にファンになってきちゃいかん
It's kiss-ish, it's kiss-ish, actually, I've become a fan.
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器
It's small, it's small, the vessel.
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね
It's small, it's small,
天才ゆえ孤独でしょ
Because of genius, it's lonely, isn't it?
"カッケェ...カッケェ！"
"So cool... so cool!"
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's God-ish, that's cowardly.
神っぽいな それ "my god"
It's God-ish, that's "my god".
超健康 健康 言い張ってくたばっていく感じ
Super healthy, healthy, and I'm going to die with the feeling of holding on.
ヤケっぽいな それ 畢竟
It's desperate-ish, that's, after all.
ヤケっぽいな それ "my god"
It's desperate-ish, that's "my god".
もう哀愁 哀愁 エピゴーネンの日居る
Melancholy, melancholy, is there an epigone?
そのタイトル その絵 その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, that picture, that music, that song, that melody.
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯
It's that-ish, that's cowardly.
アレっぽいな それ
It's that-ish, that...
その名言 その意見 その批評
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism,
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense.
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's God-ish, that's cowardly.
ぽいな ぽいな ぽいな 憧れちゃう！
Sounds like that, sounds like that, sounds like that, I yearn for it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
ぴかない ぴかない
It sounds like that, it sounds like that.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
風
Wind.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Too turu too too turu...
神っぽいな
It's God-ish.
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぴかない
Love's spoiler, "Separation" sounds like that.
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぴかない
Life's spoiler, "Death" sounds like that.
すべて理解して病悩んだ
I understood everything and became ill.
無邪気に踊っていたかった
I wanted to keep dancing innocently.
「人生」
"Life".
いや、いいんだよ、プロデューサーの好みとか！
Yeah, it's fine. The producer's preference, or...
聞いたのは、そっちです
You're the one who brought it up.
ちょっとちょっと、ケンカしてどうしたの！
Hey, hey, hey! What happened, having a fight?
あっ、こよちゃーん！！！聞いてよープロデューサーのやつが～！！！
Listen, Koyori-chan! Listen to this, the producer's...
うんうん
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
それで、あいつがさ～～！！
And then, that guy...
そうだね～ラブちゃん辛かったね～
Is that so? Luv-chan, that must have been tough~.
はぁ。ここまでいろんなホロメンと絡んできたけど
Phew. I've gotten involved with all sorts of holomem up to now,
やっぱりこよちゃんが一番だよ！！
but Koyori-chan is definitely the best!
そうだ！今度の西暦の生誕ライブ一緒に出ようよ！
That's right! Next time, let's both appear in the upcoming hololive birthday live!
こよちゃんと西暦にぴったりな曲があるんだ！
I've got just the song that fits you and me, Koyori-chan!
ライブの出演ね！スケジュール…確認しておくね～！
A live appearance? Let me check my schedule...
ありがとー！じゃあまたステージで！！
Thanks! See you on stage again!!
(俺、このライブが終わったら…君と…)
(I, once this live is over... with you...)
横画面で開始します
Starting in horizontal mode.
時計のハリが
Until the ticking of the clock
12から12に回るまで
spins from 12 to 12 again,
頭ん中が 染められていく ぴんこすてぃっくLuv
the inside of my head is being dyed with Pink Stick Luv.
すれ違ったり ふと目と目が交わるだけで
Just by passing by, or suddenly our eyes meeting,
宙に浮いてる気分になる
I feel like I'm floating in mid-air.
でもそんなこと君は知らないし Say yeah!
But you don't know that. Say yeah!
手を繋ぎたい キスをしたい
I want to hold hands, I want to kiss,
君と半径10メートル以内で
within a 10-meter radius of you.
も叶わないから妄想で
But it won't come true, so it's all in my delusions.
今日も蛇口とキスの練習day
Today is another day of practicing kissing with the faucet.
君のことに一喜一憂 だって好きだから！
I'm up and down over you, because I like you!
こっち向いて、待って待って、やっぱ向いて！
Look this way, wait wait, look this way after all!
独り占めしたいの
I want you all to myself.
こっち向いて、ワガママだって
Look this way, I know I'm being selfish,
わかってるけど だってだってだってだって
but, but, but, but...
目が合って、高なって、赤くなって、
Our eyes meet, my heart races, my face turns red,
百面相してるの
I'm having a hundred fantasies.
今日だって君のせいで
Even today, because of you,
ドキドキ忙しい どうしてくれるの
I'm busy with a pounding heart, why do you do this to me?
サンデーマンデー チューしてギューして
Sunday, Monday, kiss me, squeeze me.
毎日クリンイミティケキューチ
Every day, a clingy love, a love I want to keep.
健気さキューティー 一途にウォッチ
The cuteness of being single-minded, watching over you.
あっちそっちこっち向いて どっち？！
This way, that way, look this way, which way?!
早まる鼓動のBPM
My pounding heart's BPM.
時計のハリが12から12に回るまで
The ticking clock is spinning round from 12 to 12,
頭ん中が染められていくぴんこすてぃっくLuv
and the inside of my head is clouded by your pink stick luv.
すれ違ったり ふと目と目が交わるだけで
When we pass each other or our eyes meet for a second,
宙に浮いてる気分になる でもそんなこと君は知らないし
it feels like I'm floating on air, but you don't know that.
Say yeah
手を繋ぎたい キスをしたい
I want to hold your hands, I want to kiss you,
君と半径10メートル以内で叶わないから妄想で
within 10 meters of you, but since I can't, in my daydreams...
今日も蛇口とキスの練習day
It's practice kissing the faucet again today.
君のことに一喜一憂 だって好きだから！
I'm on edge over you because I like you!
こっち向いて、まてまて、やっぱ向いて！独り占めにしたいの
Look this way, wait, look at me! I want you all to myself!
こっち向いて、わがままで、わかってるけど だってだってだってだって
Look this way, I know I'm being selfish, but hey, hey, hey!
目が合って、高鳴って、赤くなって、百面相してるの
Our eyes meet, my heart races, my face turns red, I'm making faces!
今日だって君のせいで ドキドキ忙しいどうしてくれるの
Today because of you, my heart is pounding like crazy!
sunday monday ちゅーしてきゅーして 毎日クリンチ射抜きけい貧窮
Sunday Monday, kiss me, squeeze me, everyday you pierce my heart.
健気さcutey 一途にwatch
Devoted cutey, watching you with all my heart.
あっちそっちこっち向いてどっち？！
Looking here and there, which way should I look?!
早まる鼓動のbpm
My heart's beating faster and faster.
日に日に好きになるsml
Day by day I like you more, SML.
わかってよなんて自分勝手 やっぱりきっぱりとびきりのluv
Understand me, how selfish, but this is my ultimate luv!
新鮮なこの思いトワインクル 君に伝えたい「ぴんこす」
Sparkling with fresh emotions, I want to tell you my feelings.
脳内占領レベルは最強 手付けず勉強許して？ご愛嬌
Brain occupancy level is max, forgive my lack of studying!
胸のトキメキも絶頂 待ちに待った今日
The fluttering in my chest is at its peak, today is the day!
君とランチデートご一緒 なんて妄想で済ます憂いのshow
Having a lunch date with you, or so I daydream in this show.
こっち向いて、まてまて、やっぱ向いて 恥ずかしいだけど
Look this way, wait, look at me, even though it's embarrassing.
こっち向いて 君の目に映った自分の顔が赤い気がして
Look this way, I feel like my face in your eyes is red.
目が合って、手が触れて、それだけで一大事件なんてもう
Our eyes meet, our hands touch, that alone is a huge deal.
ねぇ だって「君のことが」この先がどうしてなのか言えないの
Hey, but why can't I say "I love you" and what comes next?
まぶたの裏想い浮かべて 好きだよ 好きなの ねぇ 想うだけで幸せなの
Picturing you in my mind, just thinking of you makes me happy.
本当はちょっと切ない 口を出る強がり 見抜いて寂しがり 実はもう限界
Actually it's a bit painful, these defiant words hiding my pain.
越えんのだけれど 言えるはずない 言えるわけない
I want to cross the line, but there's no way I can say it.
臆病なハートにあと押ししてwant me?
Give a cowardly heart a little push, want me?
こっち向いて、まてまて、やっぱ向いて 独り占めにしたいの
Look this way, wait, look at me, I want you all to myself!
こっち向いて、わがままで、わかってるけど だってだってだってだって
Look this way, I know I'm being selfish, but hey, hey, hey!
目が合って、高鳴って、赤くなって、百面相してるの
Our eyes meet, my heart races, my face turns red, I'm making faces!
今日だって君のせいで ドキドキ忙しい神様お願い
Today because of you, my heart is pounding, dear God please.
ちょっとでいいから 勇気をください 勘違いまぐろ
Just a little bit, please give me courage, misunderstood tuna.
プロデューサー あぁ！！！
Producer: Aaah!!!
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
こよちゃんにフラれたぁ〜
Koyo-chan rejected meee~
フラれるとこあるんですね？
You can get rejected?
ちくしょう！！！こうなったら！！！
Damn it!!! If it's going to be like this!!!
誰でもいいから付き合いた〜い！！
I want to date anyoneee!!
そうなったらもう終わりですよ
If you do that, it's over for you.
うるさい！わが輩は彼女作って幸せになるんだー!!!!!
Shut up! I'm going to get a girlfriend and be happy!!!!!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me!
誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
もう 誰でもいいから
I don't care who, somebody go out with me!
男の前では喋れても
I can talk fine in front of guys,
女の前では喋れない
but I can't talk in front of girls.
トラウマだらけの僕の過去 涙なしでは語れない
My trauma-filled past cannot be spoken without tears.
どうして彼女ができないの？ 僕は素敵だと君は言う
"Why can't I get a girlfriend?" You say I'm wonderful.
それなら僕と付き合ってよ その苦笑いの意味はなに
"Then go out with me." What does that bitter smile mean?
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me!
もう 誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
なんで...泣くんだよ...ハハ...
Why... are you crying... haha...
全員からフラれたぁぁ~~~！！！
Rejected by everyoneee~~~!!!
うーん、このライブ、大丈夫かな
Hmm, I wonder if this live is gonna be okay.
くそ、もうこうなったら！
Damn it, if it comes to this!
この封印を…解放してやるぅ！！！
I'll release this seal...!
俺の聖植を…爆裂させてやるぅ！！！ウォーーー！！！
I'll make my holy plant explode! Waaah!!!
お、おしまいこのライブは…もはやライブなのかも怪しい所…
Th-this live is over... Is this even a live anymore...
なんていうか大きな声で言うことではないかもしれないが
It might not be something to say in a loud voice,
男女に備わったあれとそれ 正と乱とのおいわいあれとそれ
that and this bestowed upon men and women,
そんなこんなで起こるhappening あっという間に僕のending
happenings that occur just like that,
ヤマって悩んで困ってしまってどうしようって何もできない無情
and my ending in the blink of an eye.
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって真っ赤なmy sunshine
The 0.02mm wall becomes terribly frustrating,
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
wanting to put it in right away is your fault.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
Welcoming you and me with a vibe like "Sure, why not?"
あ、しまったって思ったってもう遅い Upside inside out. I defend you.
Upside inside out. I defend you.
甘噛みyouの髪 いっさいがっさいは愛で返事
Nibbling your hair, responding to everything with love.
I'm coming. You're coming. 待ってこいってこいって僕のせい?
I'm coming. You're coming. Is it my fault?
生でいいよって言った君のせい?
Is it your fault for saying raw is fine?
そして5分で終わるテストってシンピョウセケ欠けるもんだって
And a test that ends in 5 minutes lacks credibility.
しっかり刻まれた十字架に張り付けられた僕はけり捨てに
Nailed to the firmly carved cross, I am thrown away.
0.02mmの壁がすげー悩ましくなって真っ青なmy sunshine
The 0.02mm wall becomes terribly agonizing,
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
wanting to put it in right away is your fault.
上々とかそんな気分で解消もないこんな身分で
In such a status with no resolution, feeling top-notch—
泣いたって怒ったって後の祭り Maximum insertなう。 Are you ready?
Maximum insert now. Are you ready?
愛撫ハニー 指噛み 聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Caressing honey, biting fingers, Holy Spear Explosive Boy.
愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming. 遠い夏の思い出 君の長い髪が揺れる
Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
待ってこいってこいって僕のせい? 中に出してって言った君のせい?
Wait, is it my fault? Is it your fault for saying cum inside?
そして5分で終わるテストって絶対的二元論だって
And a test that ends in 5 minutes is absolute dualism.
十月十日ばかりの運命を支配している僕は神様になれないって無理ってわかっていて結局何も解決してない
Knowing I can't be a god, in the end I've resolved nothing.
待ってこれって僕の背中にだしてって言った君のせい?
Wait, is this your fault for telling me to put it on my back?
そして5分で終わるテストって絶対的にエローなって
And a test that ends in 5 minutes is utterly erotic.
日付変わったばかりの本命を支配している僕は神様になれないって無理ってわかっていて結局何も解決してない
Knowing I can't be a god, in the end I've resolved nothing.
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって真っ白なmy sunshine
The 0.02mm wall becomes terribly frustrating,
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
wanting to put it in right away is your fault.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンでしまったって思ったってもう遅い
Welcoming you with a vibe like "Sure, why not?" in that heaven.
Upside inside out. I defend you. 甘噛みyouの髪
Upside inside out. I defend you. Nibbling your hair.
いっさいがっさいは愛で返事 I'm coming. You're coming.
Giving back everything with love. I'm coming. You're coming.
最大限愛してちょうだい 愛撫ハニー 指噛み
Please love me to the max, caressing honey, biting fingers,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ 愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming.
Holy Spear Explosive Boy. Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
いやぁ、まさか、聖槍でライブ会場壊しちゃうなんて……
Man, I never expected to wreck the venue with the holy spear...
つい…力を解放してしまった…
I accidentally... unleashed my power...
それにしても、みんなひどくない？我が輩をフルなんて…
Even so, isn't everyone being harsh? Dumping me like that...
もうやってらんないよ～
I'm totally done with this~
（ここはあの方を使うしかない）
(I have no choice but to use that person here.)
ラプラスさん、実は、あの方に来ていただいてます！
La+-san, actually, we've had that person come over!
あの方？
That person?
ラプくん？どうしたの～？
Lap-kun? What's wrong?
うわっ！？あ、あ、あじゅ姉！？まさか、我が輩のために来てくれたの？？？？
Whoa!? Did you really come here for my sake????
当然だよー！だって今日は、ラプくんの誕生日でしょー？
Of course! Today is Lap-kun's birthday, right?
あ、やばい。我が輩、今日が命日かもしれない……
Oh crap. Today might actually be my last day...
お誕生日おめでとう！プレゼントは何がいなか～？
Happy birthday! What kind of present would you like?
え！プレゼントってなんでももらえるの？！
Eh! You mean I can get anything as a present?!
あじゅがあげられるものなら何でも大丈夫だゾ☆
Anything that Aju can give is totally fine☆
えーー！？ふーー、じゃあ……
Eeeeeh!? Whew, well then...
え？今なんて言ったの？変な音で聞こえなかった！
Huh? What did you just say? It sounded weird!
あれ？
Huh?
なんだこれー！届かないぞ、我が輩の願いが！
What is this?! My wish isn't getting through!
あぶない…危うく配信できないところだった…
That was close... We almost couldn't stream...
邪魔するなプロデューサー！！！！！
Don't get in my way, Producer!!!!!
なんか色々大変そうだから…今日はこの辺で帰るね！今日は本当にめでと～！ラプくん、また遊ぼうね～
I'm heading home around here! Happy birthday!
なんか色々大変そうだから…今日はこの辺で帰るね!今日は本当にめおでと~!ラプくん、また遊ぼうね~
...today is really a milestone! Lap-kun, let's play again soon~
あ、お、おじゅねえ!
Ah, wait!
おじゅねえええええ!!!!
Wait! Wait!
Prrrr
Prrr...
え、はい、はい、分かりました!
Y-Yes, hello, I understand!
ラプラスさん「新曲オーディション」でっす!
Laplus-san, a new song audition?!
と、いうこと?
What do you mean?!
新曲だけのオーディション大会があって、そこで優勝したら、大型コラボでっす!今すぐ曲準備します!
If you win, it's a huge collaboration! I'll get the song ready right away!
ダンスレッスンいれますね!
Dance lessons sound great!
今から新曲?ダンスレッスン?
A dance lesson for a new song right now?!
ま、間に合うのそれ?
W-Will we make it in time?
もうライブまでちょっとしかしないよ?
We barely have any time left until the live!
間に合わせてください!もしオーディションに合格したら大型コラボなんですよ!!
Please make it in time! If you win the audition, it's a huge collaboration, you know!!
えー!!喉も疲れたんですけど!!!!!
Eeeh!! My throat is already exhausted!!
大型コラボってなんなの!
What kind of huge collaboration is this?!
それはまだ、秘密です。
That is still a secret.
なんでだよおおお!!!!
Whyyyyyy!!
…はぁ…はぁっ、はぁっ、はぁっ、体力ないって言ってるのに…走り込み…？
*Pant, pant, pant...* You said I don't have stamina, yet... running...?
だからこその走り込みです!
That's precisely why we're doing it!
…はぁ この筋トレ、本当に意味あるの?
*Pant* Does this muscle training really mean anything?
…だっっ…はぁっ、あぁあっ…
...Hck, hah... aaaaaah!
よし、良い感じだ!
Alright, looking good!
ラプラスさん!本番前に行きましょう!あの方の元へ!
Laplus-san, let's go see that person before the main event!
あ、あの方?!
Ah, that person?!
わぁい!よーし、行こう!
Owaah! Alright, let's go!
チョコ先生!
Choco-sensei!
あら、いらっしゃいラプちゃん。
Oh, welcome, Lap-chan.
どれにするの?
Which one should I pick?
悩んじゃうよね…
I'm having trouble choosing...
わかるわかる。
I know, I know.
答えは1つじゃないからねえ。
The answer isn't just one, you know?
ラプちゃん真剣に考えたもんねえ。
Lap-chan thought about it seriously, right?
全部ちゃんと見たいの?
You want to see all of them properly, right?
じゃあ、皆さんお疲れのグッズ情報よ!
Then, here is the merchandise info for everyone's hard work!
ラプラス・ダークネス 誕生日記念2026グッズ!
Laplus Darkness Birthday Celebration 2026!
順番に紹介していきます!
We'll introduce them in order!
じゃーん、まずはこれ、カードアルバム!
First is this, the Card Album!
特典の、あのチェキ風ブロマイドカードとかホロカとかを収納できるアルバムです!
It's an album that can store special bromide cards, holocards, and more!
えっと、めっちゃ久しぶりにクロ先生が、えっと、我が儘のママね、クロネママが、えっと、描き下ろしてくれましたイラスト!
It's been a long time since Choco-sensei—well, since Waga-mama—Waga-mama drew the illustration for us!
いぇーい!めっちゃかわいい!
Yay! So cute!
かわいいでしょ?
Right?
いやこのアルバムぎゅってしてんのもまたいいでしょ?
And having this album squeezed tight like that is nice too, right?
そう、でしょ?
That's true.
これもちゃんと、あのアルバムをぎゅっと。
This one also has that album squeezed tight.
描いてくれたやつ。
Drawn by Shiroko-sensei.
じゃあこれ買ったら、そう、ラプちゃんがぎゅっとしたアルバムが手に入るってこと?
So if you buy this, you get an album of Lap-chan squeezing it?
え?それはあの、商品、しょうひんけいしょうができます!
Uhh, that's product info... well, you can recreate it!
二つ目はこれ!こうふんボイスキーホルダー!
Second is this, the Voice Keychain!
え、毎回お馴染みの取り下ろしボイスが6種類入ったキーホルダーです!
It's a keychain with 6 types of our usual recorded voicemails!
え、押すと声が出ます、いつもの通り!今回も、しろこ先生の描き下ろしです!
When you press it, your voice plays, just like always, and this time it's Shiroko-sensei's recorded voice!
めろめろな表情をしたオリジナルの寝巻き姿です。
It features a sleepy-eyed expression in her original pajamas appearance.
どっと声が出る。
You can hear groggy voices.
はい。
Right?
えーー!えー!どこを押せばいいのかな!
Eeeh?! Which one should I press?!
えー、三つ目は、三つ目はこっち!
The third one, the third one is here!
え、ばぶらぷらすぬいぐるみ!
The Lapu-Laplas Plushie!
です。えっと、おしゃべりおしゃぶりを加えて、ベビーベアを着て寝ている我が輩のぬいぐるみでございます。
It's a plushie of Waga-haha wearing a baby bear suit and sleeping while babbling.
え、めっちゃかわいい!
So cute!
チョコもぎゅってしたい!
Choco-sensei wants to squeeze it too!
ちょこ、ん、そ、そんな、ぎゅってして!いつでも、いつでも!
You can squeeze it anytime! Anytime!
あぁ〜!あぁ、いい匂いする!くんくん。もうやめてやめて!
Ah, it smells so good! Please stop sniffing!
もう、まずいまずい!
It smells so bad, so bad!
四つ目はこっち!
The fourth one is here!
あ、そうそうそう。あ、合っちゃった。え、ばぶらぷらすのぬいぐるみをつめるハンカチです!
It's a handkerchief to wrap the Lapu-Laplas Plushie!
さっきのぬいぐるみをつめて、
You wrap the plushie we just talked about,
あとは普通にハンカチとしても使えます。
and you can also use it as a regular handkerchief.
あ、じゃあおくるみとして使えるってことね?そうです。
So you can use it as swaddling clothes? Exactly!
かわいい!でか、でかっ、でかいす、こんなかないす、こんなね?
It's so cute! And it's pretty big! There's nothing else quite like it, right?
そして最後に、フルセット購入特典として、え、我がママクロネママ描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきまーす!
And finally, as a full-set purchase bonus, a bromide card featuring Waga-mama's illustration will be included!
はい、そして数量限定バージョンは、はい、書きますサインを。直筆サインとクセメッセージが入ってます!
Yes, and the quantity-limited version includes a direct copy signature and a special message!
通常バージョンは、おっきーの複製サインとメッセージが入ってるよ。
The regular version includes Okki's duplicate signature and message.
この配信の後には販売開始だから
Sales start right after this stream, so
みんなよろしくねー！
everyone please look forward to it!
お願いしまーす！
Thank you so much!
以上、グッズ紹介なんですけど
That's the merch introduction, but
おき先生、ありがとうございます。
Oki-sensei, thank you very much.
えーこちらこそー！
Eh, thank you too!
これからちょっとオーディションなんだ新曲の。
This is kind of an audition for the new song.
応援してね、ラプラスちゃん。
Cheer for me, Laplus-chan.
がんばって！
Do your best!
がんばります！ありがとー！
I'll do my best! Thank you!
あ、お姉さま！あの、今日ライブなのにバカハイお風呂入ってないんですけど、おねがいがあって…
Ah, Oneesama! Um, today's a live and I haven't bathed in three days, but I have a favor...
あの、耳舐めてほしいですっ！
Um, I want you to lick my ears!
お姉さま♡
Oneesama♡
ああお姉さま♡
Ah, Oneesama♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa, Oneesama♡
お姉さま♡ああお姉さま♡
Oneesama♡ Ah, Oneesama♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま~~~!
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!
世の中のお姉さまに捧ぐ
Dedicated to the older sisters of the world
起きたら耳元で囁いて
Whisper in my ear when I wake up
胸元に滴るその汗を
The sweat dripping down your chest
ツノツノツノツノ掴んでちょうだい
Grab my horns, please
ハンドル代わりにを・を・を！
Use them like a steering wheel!
あ、お姉さまと視聴者のさけ、こんな歌ライブで歌わせてごめんなさい！
Ah, Oneesama and viewers, sorry for making me sing such a song live!
あ、お正月、お正月ください！
Ah, New Year, give me New Year!
尻から手突っ込んでガタガタ言わせてくださいノースノー！
Stick your hand up my butt and make me chatter!
あ、お姉さま今日２杯目ですた！
Ah, Oneesama, it's your second cup today!
盛り上がってきましたね！えっ、お姉さま、そこじゃないじゃん！あ、お姉さま、あ、お背中になっております！
It's getting exciting! Eh, Oneesama, not there! Ah, Oneesama, you're on my back!
ありがたや、ありがたやほいって
Thank you, thank you, hooray
望って、お姉さま！
I wish, Oneesama!
雑魚、雑魚言ってくださいの
Call me small fry
残さず飲み込むぞ
Swallow it all down
愛のムチ、ムチ愛のムチ
Whip of love, whip of love
お願いなぶって、お姉さま！
Please tease me, Oneesama!
キモくてごめんなさい
Sorry for being creepy
ありのままでキャストオフ！
Cast off just as I am!
お姉さま♡
Oneesama♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa, Oneesama♡
お姉さま♡ああお姉さま♡
Oneesama♡ Ah, Oneesama♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま~~~!
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!
刮目せよ、YMDはもう古い！
Open your eyes, YMD is old!
時代はYSOだ！YSOとは何か！？
The era is YSO! What is YSO!?
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！だーっ！
A ridiculously sexy Oneesama! Da!
YSO! YSO! YSO! ...
ほんわかドジっ子姐御肌、クーデレツンデレ小悪魔系
Fluffy clumsy bossy type, kuudere tsunere little devil type
いろんな姉がいるけれど、あらあらウフフが優勝ですw
There are all kinds of sisters, but ara-ara ufufu is victory w
もち肌ぷにぷに太ももスリスリギュッてして、居なきゃ無理無理ィィ！
Mochi skin punipuni thighs surisuri gyutte shite, if you're not here it's impossible!
ああんだ、お姉さまがいない世界なんて耐えられないでちゅうう！！！
Ah, I can't bear a world without Oneesama desu!!!
そして、吾輩は、赤ちゃんになった。
And so, I became a baby.
なでなで、よしよしされる幸せな世界。
A happy world of being petted and coddled.
今日もまた、お姉さまの太ももに顔をうめ、涎を垂らす。
Today too, I bury my face in Oneesama's thighs and drool.
これが、人生なのだ。
This is life.
キモく正しく美しく、おいでって言って
Creepily, correctly, beautifully, say "come here"
お姉さま、抱っこだ閉じてください
Oneesama, hug me, close it please
本能が剥き出しぞ
Instincts are bare
脚のムチ胸のムチ、失礼しますお姉さま
Thighs' muchi, chest's muchi, excuse me Oneesama
全裸でごめんなさい
Sorry for being naked
ありのままでキャストオフ！
Cast off just as I am!
愛してます、お姉さま♡
I love you, Oneesama♡
お姉さま♡ああお姉さま♡すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Oneesama ♡ Ah Oneesama ♡ Suu-haa suu-haa Oneesama ♡
お姉さま♡ああお姉さま♡やたらセクシーなお姉さま♡
Oneesama ♡ Ah Oneesama ♡ Yatara sexy Oneesama ♡
おーねーえーさ-ま~~~!!!
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!!!
ということで
With that said,
新曲を披露させていただきました。
I've just debuted my new song!
タイトルは
The title is...
お姉様…お姉様…ラブコードです。
"Oneesama... Oneesama... Love Code."
ちゃんと「お姉様」の後に、ハートがつくってやつです。
It's the one where a heart comes after "Oneesama".
ビートまりおさんとまのさんに作っていただきました。
Produced by Beat Mario and Mano-san!
依頼した時は、なんか…
When I requested it, like...
最近のラプラスさんを見てたら、なんか楽しく作れましたみたいなの作ってくれました。
they said watching recent Laplus-san made it really fun to write.
とんでもない曲になっちゃったぜ。
It turned out to be an outrageous song!
収録の時も、あ、これはまあ後でリリースされるんですけど、
During recording—well, this will be released later, but—
その、なんかね、収録する時もね「もっとキモく！もっとうちなるお姉様への想いを込めながら歌ってください！」とか言われて
even while recording, they were like, "Sing it creepier! Put more of your inner Oneesama passion into it!"
あんなディレクションは初めてでした。
I'd never received direction like that before.
そんな曲が、この後…え、MVがね、私のこのチャンネルでプレミア公開されますよおん！
And that song will have its premiere MV release on this channel right after!
そして、まあ今日25日なんですけれど、明日26日に日付が変わった瞬間に、この後曲がリリースされてしまいます。
And today is the 25th, but the moment the date changes to tomorrow the 26th, this song will be released.
さらに、なんと…ま、これはね、ちょっとサムネイルにもね、ちょっと釣りみたいな感じでね、重大告知みたいな感じで書いたんですけど、
And what's more... I put this in the thumbnail as a bit of clickbait, like "Major Announcement," but...
なんと…ついに私、ラプラス・ダークネス、1人で初めてのアルバムが発売されるぜええ！イェーイ！
finally, I, Laplus Darknesss, am releasing my very first solo album! Yay!
いやあなんか、1年に1曲しかオリジナル曲出さなかったのに、去年狂ったようにオリジナル曲出して、今年も出して、アルバムが出せるようになるなんてね、感慨深いものでございます。
I mean, I used to release only one original song a year, but last year I went crazy releasing them, and doing it again this year... to be able to release an album is just so deeply moving.
そして、なんと今回は2種類出るんだけど、え、1つ目がね…
And this time, there are two versions! The first one is...
ラプラス・ダークネス1stアルバム『ラプ様アーティスト化計画』高いやつ！
the Laplus Darknesss 1st Album, "Lap-sama Artistification Project"—the expensive version!
で、もう1つがラプラス・ダークネスアーティスト化計画安いやつ！
And the other one is the "Lap-sama Artistification Project"—the cheap version!
ええと、まあちょっとお金を…持っているお友達用のアルバムと…
So, um... one for friends who have a bit of money...
まあ、ちょっとママにお願いして、ママ買ってみたいな感じでお願いできそうな値段の、まあ、ホロライブで出てるアルバムだと一番安いんじゃない？っていうぐらい安いやつの2種類があるよ。
and one at a price where you can ask your mom, "Mom, can you buy this for me?"—probably the cheapest album Hololive has ever put out! There are these two versions.
え、この配信の後からホロライブ公式ショップで予約開始だから、みんな予約してね！
Reservations open on the Hololive Official Shop right after this stream, so everyone go reserve yours!
詳しくはホームページをチェック！さっき披露した新曲ももちろんアルバムに入るぜ。
Check the homepage for details! And of course, the new song I just debuted will be on the album too.
じゃ、新曲オーディション終わったらさ、あとは結果待つだけなんで、みんなバイバイ！
Well, once the new song auditions are done, all that's left is to wait for the results. Bye-bye everyone!
あ、なんかさ…なんか優勝したらさ、ご褒美って言ってたんだっけか？
Oh, and... didn't they say there's a reward if I win?
やりましたね！優勝ですよ！
We did it! You won!
さすがにレッスンとか急ぎすぎたって…もうヘトヘト…
With lessons and everything rushed like this... I'm exhausted...
…はい、分かりました！
...Yes, I understand!
ラプラスさん…
Laplus-san...
今すぐいきますよ！！！大型コラボの現場へ！！！
We're heading out right now! To the massive collab site!
え？なに？え、なにに？どこ行くのー？？？
Eh? What? Wh- What? Where are we going?!
みなさーん！こんばんはー！
Everyone! Good evening!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
短い時間だけど、一緒に楽しもうね！
It's a short time, but let's enjoy it together!
今日は特別なゲストが来てくれています！
Today, we have a special guest visiting us!
ホロライブのラプラス・ダークネスさんです！
It's Hololive's Laplus Darknesss-san!
うれし…
So happy...
リノミ姐さん、リノミ姐さん…！
Rinami-neesan, Rinami-neesan...!
あ、ほんとに、あ、ほんとに…リノミさん…
Ah, really, ah, really... Rinami-san...
ほんとにリノミさんですか…？
Are you really Rinami-san...?
はい！
Yes!
はじめまして…
Nice to meet you...
あ、はじめまして
Ah, nice to meet you.
今日はご一緒できて光栄です！
It's an honor to perform together today!
あ、はい！
Ah, yes!
なんて呼んだらいいですか？
What should I call you?
あの、もう敬語、あ、敬語やめてください、あのラプくんって呼んでください
Um, you can stop using honorifics... please call me Lap-kun.
わかいも…
Young one...
リノミお姉さじゅ…って呼んでもいいですか…？
C-can I call you Rinami-onee-san...?
もちろん！リノミお姉さんって呼んでくれると嬉しいな！
Of course! I'd be so happy if you called me Rinami-onee-san!
ラプくん！
Lap-kun!
ちょっと、リノミお姉さじゅ…はい！ラプくん！
Wait, Rinami-onee-san... Yes! Lap-kun!
今日は私の曲を披露させてもらうんだけど、ラプくんも会場を盛り上げるためにちょっとだけ一緒に参加してくれるんだよね？
Today I get to showcase my song, but Lap-kun, you'll join me a bit to hype up the venue, right?
はい、あの、恐縮です。本当はちょっとこんな近くで見れるだけでも嬉しいんですけど…
Yes, um, I'm honored. Honestly, I'm happy just being able to watch from this close...
微力ながら参加させていただきます
Though it's a small contribution, I'll gladly participate.
うん！一緒に共演できて嬉しいよ！素敵なライブになるといいね！
Yeah! I'm so happy we get to perform together! I hope it becomes a wonderful live!
それじゃ、早速1曲披露させてもらおうかな？
Well then, shall we showcase our first song right away?
ラプくん、準備はいい？
Lap-kun, are you ready?
はい、おもちゃです！あの、行きます！準備します！あ、行きます！
Yes, I'm ready! Um, let's go! I'm getting ready! Ah, let's go!
みんなも一緒に楽しもうね！
Everyone, let's enjoy this together too!
それでは1曲目、聴いてください！
And now, please listen to our first song!
i know 愛のボーダー
i know, love's border
今日は少しだけ飛び越えてみちゃおうか
Today, let's try leaping just a little bit over it!
全然始まんない物語を見ているような気分
It feels like watching a story that's not starting at all
焦れな君にお知らせします このままいけばエンドロールで you＝エクストラa
I'm letting you know, impatient one. If things go on like this, in the end roll, you = extra!
すぐ逸らすその目も 待てど出ないロマンスの芽も
That gaze that quickly looks away, and the buds of romance that don't appear no matter how long I wait
「いっそ」「ねえねえ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」でラブもデコっちゃう？
"Shall we?" "Hey hey, can I borrow your forehead♪" and decorate our love too?
急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute 彼のcue受け取ってよ
With a sudden "hug", cute heart, receive his cue!
想像超えてく展開見てみたいの 私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
I want to see developments beyond imagination. Isn't making the first move from me too cliché?
36℃ウブな君にcaution！ もうちょい私にお熱を上げて欲しいのです
Caution to you, who is 36°C naive! I want you to turn up the heat on me a bit more.
君にとって私は一体何なの？ はい、ど～こからは君の番
What on earth am I to you? Yes, from here on is your turn.
上手く言おうとなんてしないで ちょっと不自然くらいじゃなきゃ 恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
Don't try to say it too smoothly. If it's not a bit unnatural, love has no way of starting like that.
かくかくしかじか…つまりはlove song 出来不出来は横に置いて痴情をご希望
Thus and so... in other words, a love song. Put performance aside, I desire passion!
ちょっとhighな熱いloveにうなされてみない？ キホン野基本 恋の三大cha cha cha
Why don't you suffer from a slightly high, passionate love? The basics of basics, love's three major cha-cha-chas.
chance・chase・challenge 用のないメッセージ さりげないタッチ
chance, chase, challenge, a message with no purpose, a casual touch
翻訳すればすべてがつまりラビュ～ 頭で考えずに脊髄反射で応えて
Translate it all and it means "I love you". Don't think with your head, respond with spinal reflexes!
no no だけで能がないよ そうよあとちょっと もう一歩
Just saying "no no" shows no skill. That's right, just a little bit more, one more step.
3・2・1で cha cha cha cha cha ♪ やればできる子素直でよろしい
At 3, 2, 1, cha cha cha cha cha ♪ A good boy who can do it if he tries, obedient and lovely!
36℃ニブい君にcaution！ 「どうせ・だって・でもでも」なんて3Dを抜け出して
Caution to you, who is 36°C dense! Break out of 3D with "anyway, but, but-but"
異次元的ステキをいっぱい感じて はい、ど～こからは君の番
Feel the otherworldly wonderfulness to the fullest. Yes, from here on is your turn.
「違うかも…」なんて構えないで ちょっとくらいの勘違いじゃなきゃ 恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
Don't hold back thinking "Maybe I'm wrong..." Unless there's a little bit of misunderstanding, love has no way of starting like that.
「ねえねえ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」でラブもデコっちゃう？ 急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute 彼のcue受け取ってよ
"Hey hey, can I borrow your forehead♪" and decorate our love too? With a sudden "hug", cute heart, receive his cue!
予感に身を委ねてみたいの 私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
I want to surrender myself to the premonition. Isn't making the first move from me too cliché?
36℃ウブな君にcaution！ もうちょい私にお熱を上げて欲しいのです
Caution to you, who is 36°C naive! I want you to turn up the heat on me a bit more.
余裕に見えて私もいっぱいいっぱいではい、少し本音を打ち明けてしまう
Even though I look calm, I'm at my wit's end, so yes, I'll reveal a bit of my true feelings.
完璧なお姉さんだって ちょっとくらいの隙がなくちゃ 好きになんてなれるはずがないものでしょう？
Even a perfect big sister needs a little gap, otherwise there's no way you could fall in love with her, right?
だから君を… “スキ”だらけで待っています いつだってちょっとhighな熱いloveにうなされてみて
That's why I'm waiting for you... full of openings, whenever you are, try suffering from a slightly high, passionate love!
36度U・B・Uの君に逢うと
When I meet you at 36° U・B・U
ちょっともうじゃわ私に熱は上げてほしいので
I want you to be even more passionate about me
夜に見えて私もういっぱい
Looking like night, I'm already full
いっぱいで最初々本音ではぶっちゃけちゃうと
Full to the brim, frankly speaking from the start
完璧なお姉さんだって
Even a perfect older sister
ちょっとくらいの隙じゃなくちゃ好きになれないで耐えれるはずがないものでしょう
Couldn't possibly fall in love unless there are a few flaws, right?
だから君を好きだらけで待っています
That's why I'm waiting for you, full of love
いつだってちょっとハイな祭りのように連れ去ってみたい
Whenever, I want to be carried away like a high festival
回想中 熱くなり お茶濁し？
In the midst of reminiscing, getting heated, deflecting?
紳士に 大人で ハートは君に
Gently, maturely, my heart is yours
まだ教えずに ご相談
Without telling you yet, asking for advice
チラチラと 余裕身につけて
Glancing around, wearing composure
言う「お相手はyou？」
Saying, "Is your partner you?"
ドラマのようなことしない女優
An actress who doesn't act like in dramas
噛めば噛むほど美味しいlady
The more you chew, the more delicious the lady
例に甘え方を見せてほしいの
I want you to show me how to indulge in examples
はみ出したいの
I want to overflow
うん、変われないの
Yeah, I can't change
自由型のいい子は好き放題
Good kids of the free type do as they please
その塩梅もわからないの
I don't even know that balance
優しくふりしてただ焦ってる
Acting kind while just panicking
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し
Casually deflecting demands
嬉しさを ごまかし 反省会
Hiding my happiness, reflection meeting
36度U・B・Uでした！どうだったかな？
That was 36° U・B・U! How was it?
最高でした！
It was amazing!
なんかありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
一緒にパフォーマンスしてくれて嬉しいよ
I'm so happy you performed with me!
あの、黒ココで楽しかったです
Um, it was fun with Kurococo.
あの間近でリナミさんのパフォーマンス見れてもう、もう声出ました
Seeing Rinami-san's performance up close, I couldn't help but make noise!
ありがとう
Thank you!
ええと、今日は次の曲が最後になるんだけど
Um, today the next song will be the last one, but...
えええー！はやすぎます、まだ見たいです
Ehhh! Too fast, we want to see more!
名残惜しいけど
It's a shame, but...
次の曲はみんなにも声をを出してほしいな
For the next song, I want everyone to raise their voices too!
一緒に最後まで楽しもうね
Let's enjoy it together until the very end!
もちろんです！もう声枯れるまでやります
Of course! We'll do it until our voices are hoarse!
なんか、喉は大事にしてね
Make sure to take care of your throats!
リナミお姉さん、あの我が家の先輩もどうしてもライブ見たいて言ってるんですけど呼んでいいですか？
Rinami-san, our house's senior also really wants to see the live, can we call her?
ぜひ！行こっ！行こっ！まいすいしよっ！
By all means! Let's go! Let's go! Let's do it!
ややーよろしくお願いします
Yay, thank you very much!
お願いしまーす
Please!
だからみこさん、お会いできて光栄です
So Miko-san, it's an honor to meet you!
こちらこそです！パフォーマンス楽しみにしています
Same here! Looking forward to the performance!
お姉さん、頑張っちゃうよ
Big sis will do her best!
それでは次の曲、聴いてください
Now, please listen to the next song!
駆け引きを学んだり 裏技を
Learning how to bargain, secret techniques
つらつらと 至急 きっかけのキュー！
Steadily, urgently, the cue for the start!
慌てても cute
Even when flustered, cute
そんなこと言って 仕立しない iq
Saying things like that, IQ that isn't set up
あの手この手も 出来ない lady
A lady who can't use every trick in the book
例に落とし方 まとめてほしい
I want you to summarize how to fall for you
遠慮してんじゃ無いのです
It's not that I'm holding back
その向こうの 自由がたの言うことは好き放題
What the free-spirited ones beyond say is as they please
その塩梅もわからないの
I don't even know that balance
優しくふりしてただ焦ってる
Acting kind while just panicking
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し
Casually deflecting demands
嬉しさを ごまかし 反省会
Hiding my happiness, reflection meeting
レディレディあの手の見せても欲しい
Lady lady, I want you to show me that kind of hand
一緒に歌ってくれる？
Will you sing along with me?
はみ出したいの もう耐えられないの
I want to overflow, I can't stand it anymore
自由型の言うことは好き放題
What the free type says is as they please
人の温度もう止められないの
People's warmth can't be stopped anymore
優しくふりしてただ溺れてる
Acting kind while just drowning
許されないの
It's unforgivable
優しくふりしてただ焦ってる
Acting kind while just panicking
二人ともよくできました
You both did a great job
そっと交差して君を 密会見よう
Intersect softly and have a secret meeting with you
そっと心叩く君を ああ君を
Gently knocking on my heart, you, ah you
知りたい
I want to know
はみ出したい もう耐えられない
I want to overflow, I can't stand it anymore
自由型の言うことは好き放題 人の温度もう止められない
What the free type says is as they please, people's warmth can't be stopped anymore
優しくふりしてただ焦ってもっともっと
Acting kind while panicking more and more
弾けないの 誰だってなくりーどしたいけど
Can't bounce, anyone wants to recreate-ly want, but
そのボタン もう超えられないの そもそもの話
That button can't be crossed anymore, to begin with
まだ隠して 見つめてる
Still hiding, gazing
はぁ…
Whew...
clumsy trick でした！
That was a clumsy trick!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
最高でした！最高です！
It was the best! Absolutely the best!
ラプくんとあんなふうに一緒にパフォーマンスすることになるなんて楽しかったな！
It was so fun getting to perform together
with Lap-kun like that!
よかったらこっちで一緒に話そうよ。
If you'd like, come over here
and let's talk together.
えっ！？
Eh?!
いってこいよ！ え、いやいやいや、ここが、ここがやっぱり落ち着くんですけど。
Go on! - E, no no no, this,
this is actually where I feel at ease.
さっきは一緒にステージにいてくれたのに？ 確かに、やっぱ。
Weren't you up on stage with me
just a moment ago? - True, that's true.
いってこいよ！ 呼ばれたいながら？ え、今行きます、待ってください。
Go on! - Are you being summoned?
- Uh, I'm going right now, please wait.
緊張する！
I'm so nervous!
頑張れ！
You can do it!
ふぅー。
Whew.
急に出てくるからびっくりしちゃったよ。
You popped out so suddenly,
you really surprised me!
す、すみません、なんか。もう我慢できなくて。
S-Sorry, um...
I just couldn't hold it in anymore.
そんなハプコンなところがラプくんの魅力だよね。私も見習いたいよ。
That kind of unpredictable side is part of Lap-kun's charm.
I want to learn from you too.
いや、もうルリ姉お姉さんはもうこのままで素敵です。もうこのままで行ってください。
No, Lamy-oneesan, you're already wonderful just as you are.
Please stay just like this.
ありがとう。これからもお互いアイドルとして頑張ろうね。
Thank you. Let's both keep doing our best
as idols from now on too.
あ、もう、それを。ルリ姉さん、ありがとうございます。頑張ります！
Ah, um, about that. Lamy-oneesan,
thank you very much. I'll do my best!
またこうやって一緒に共演できたら嬉しいな。
I'd be so happy if we could co-star
together like this again.
それも、もうそれを過ぎよ。ありがとうございます。頑張ります。
That too—well, let's leave it at that.
Thank you very much. I'll do my best.
今日はありがとう！とっても素敵なミニライブでした！
Thank you for today!
It was such a wonderful mini-live!
みんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
I wonder if everyone enjoyed it too?
それじゃあ、またね！ ラプくんも！ ルリ姉お姉さん！
Well then, see you later!
- Lap-kun too! - Lamy-oneesan!
お姉さ… お姉さん…
Onee-sa... Onee-san...